Many column names in databases are
named in a very technical fashion,
which makes perfect sense to a database designer
but not much sense to those who need to understand
what a column title means on a report. In those
situations, a column alias can and should be used.
For this example, I have a query with a column
called SalesOrderID, but most who work with
this data know this as an order number. Thus,
I will place the cursor just before the comma
and add the words AS 'Order Number', making
sure order number is in quotes because it
has a space in it. To make sure this works,
I will execute this statement, and it works.
As seen elsewhere in this course, table aliasing
is powerful as it offers a shortcut for using
joins and clearing ambiguities in columns used in
a query. This feature does not just apply to self
joins. To demonstrate this, I will add aliases
to both the order detail and order header tables.
Notice that I am using soh as
an alias for SalesOrderHeader
and sod as the alias for SalesOrderDetail
as consistency is key with table aliasing.
I will then change these long name
references to use the aliasing as
once a table alias is established, it
has to be used throughout the query.
The more complex your queries, the more
benefits you will get out of table aliasing.
I will execute this statement to make sure
everything still works, and yes, it does.